<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
"file:///usr/share/sgml/docbook/dtd/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY legal SYSTEM "legal.xml">
]>
<book>
  <title>
    FRDCSA Tutorial
  </title>
  <bookinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
      <surname>Dougherty</surname>
    </author>
  </bookinfo>
  <toc>
  </toc>
  <chapter>
    <title>
      Artificial Intelligence
    </title>
    <sect1>
      <title>
	Overview
      </title>
      <para>
	The  FRDCSA project  is concerned  with implementing  a public
	domain AI out of existing available free software.
      </para>
      <para>
	We define AI to be  "the evasion of chance in survival".  This
	is  achieved  by  being   able  to  solve  relatively  greater
	classes of problems.
      </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
      <title>
	Call for Assistance
      </title>
      <para>
	The first  thing we suggest is understanding  the relevance of
	this project to your daily life.
      </para>
      <para>
	By  contributing to  this project  you  will be  able to  help
	eliminate  systematic  ignorance  that  results from  lack  of
	problem solving  capabilities.  Our goal  is to reach  as many
	people as  possible, and gain a reputation  as an organization
	which  promotes  an objective  problem  solving approach  that
	helps people solve the  conflicts of interest that result from
	the  inability  to  solve  certain  problems  due  to  bounded
	rationality.  Then,  people will  become more accepting  as we
	assist them in  resolving outstanding problems that negatively
	affect their welfare and quality of life.
      </para>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>
  <chapter>
    <title>
      Universal Strategy      
    </title>
    <sect1>
      <title>
	Commandments
      </title>
      <para>
	Starting from  this point on,  you will become educated  as to
	our general  methods for  resolving problems.  In  the future,
	more  robust, intelligent  interfaces will  be  finished which
	will be  far more useful  than this simple  documentation, but
	for the purposes of having a starting point this documentation
	exists.
      </para>
      <para>
	1: Read this entire manual.
      </para>
      <para>
	In order to succeed with this system you must read this entire
	manual.
      </para>
      <para>
	Consider that when a person reads a manual, there are at least
	two  kind  of  concepts   that  they  learn.   Let  us  define
	"justified" concepts  as those  which the user  has sufficient
	knowledge to  correctly accept or  reject.  Conversely, define
	"unjustified" concepts  to be those  which the user  lacks the
	ability to correctly accept or reject.
      </para>
      <para>
	The concepts here are  often of the "unjustified" sort.  There
	are  various  common psychological  reactions  to learning  of
	unjustified  concepts, some of  which result  in understanding
	and some of which don't.
      </para>
      <para>
	The  best  strategy  is   to  treat  unjustified  concepts  as
	assertions whose  meaning is not  know currently, and  then to
	bind meaning to them as  one sees co-occurances of them in the
	text.  Then,  when their  meaning becomes completely  clear, a
	person can then decide whether  they are incorrect.
      </para>
      <para>
	Unjustified are  usually the  most novel and  informative, and
	therefore  it is  in  the readers  interest  to study  further
	despite being unsure  of the meaning of the  concepts, so that
	eventually, all  unjustified concepts have  been so thoroughly
	explained that they have  become justified concepts, which the
	user  can  then make  an  informed  decision.   But until  all
	reading has  finished, the user lacks the  correct language to
	understand the concepts.
      </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
      <title>
	Starting Points
      </title>
      <para>
	Learn GNUCash
      </para>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>
</book>

